const questions=
// ROOT INDEX
[
  // 6th Grade English
  [
    {
      "question":"I am happy to report that Grace’s baby is very ______ and ______!",
      "options": ["A.happy and healthy","B.sickly and scrawny","tiny and small","D.hungry and annoying"],
      "answer":"happy and healthy"
    },
    {
      "question":"The riverbed was _______ and ______, making it hard to balance well",
      "options": ["A.fishy and froggy","B.shallow and deep","C.moist and wet","D.rocky and slippery"],
      "answer":"rocky and slippery"
    },
    {
        "question":"She was brave _ a lion. What's the missing word",
        "options": ["A.as","B.becuase","C.before","D.so"],
        "answer":"as"
    },
     {
      "question":"The car belonging to the manager,Choose the correct answer for the following phrase",
       "options":["A.The managers car","B.The manager's car","C.The managers'car","D.The managers's car"],
       "answer":"The manager's car"

    },
    {
      "question":"James took the book; he gave it to the teacher, Choose the pronoun",
      "options":["A.book","B.he","C.James","D.teacher"],
     "answer":"Intensive"

    },
    {
      "question":"Their business's success was far greater than what even they themselves had dared to imagine",
      "options":["A.Reflexive","B.Intensive"],
     "answer":"Intensive"
   },
   {
    "question":"The root therm means heat. What does the word thermostat mean?",
    "options":["A.a device that controls the lighting a room",
              "B.a device that controls the music a room",
              "C.a device that controls the heating a room"],                                        
    "answer":"D.a device that controls the heating a room"
   },
   {
    "question":" What are homonyms?", 
    "options":["A.Words that imitate sounds or ideas",
              "B.Words that are spelled the same but in their given context have different meanings",
              "C.Words that describe, identify or further define a noun or a pronoun"],                                        
    "answer":"B.Words that are spelled the same but in their given context have different meanings"
   },
   {
    "question":"What is a metaphor?",
    "options":["A.word that replaces one or more nouns",
              "B.word that follows a conjunction",
              "C.word that shows possession",
            "D.word that is implied as being the “same” thing"],                                        
    "answer":"D.word that is implied as being the “same” thing"
    },
    {

      "question":" That meal should stick to his ribs for a while!",
      "options":["A.make him feel hungry",
      "B.last",
      "C.cause him indigestion",
      "D.remain in his stomach"],
      "answer":"B.last"
    }
  ]
]
       //6th grade Math
[
  [
    {
     "question":"7 + -3 = ?",
      "options":["A.-4","B.10","C.4","D.-10"],
     "answer":"C.4"
    },
    {
      "question":"5÷5 * 3?",
      "options":["A.3","B.15","C.1","D.4"],
      "answer":"A.3"
    },
    {
    "question":"3 * 2 + 4?",
    "options":["A.10","B.11","C.5","D.7"],
    "answer":"A.10"
     },
     {
      "question":"4 + -3 = ",
      "options":["A.2","B.1","C.-2","D.0"],
      "answer":"B.1"

     },
     {
      "question":"92,982 – 91,900 = ",
      "options":["A.1033","B.1082","C.1043","D.1039"],
      "answer":"B.1082"

     },
     {
      "question":"Is -10 × 1 positive or negative?",
      "options":["A.positive","B.negative"],
      "answer":"B.negative"
    },
    {
      "question":"Are the ratios 10:14 and 5:7 equivalent?",
      "options":["A.Yes","B.No"],
      "answer":"A.Yes"
    },
    {
      "question":"Select the ratio equivalent to  7:6?",
      "options":["A.63:54","B.21:19","C.43:36","D.77:65"],
      "answer":"A.63:54"
    },
    {
      "question":"Mark can make 42 birthday cakes in 7 days?,How many can he make in 3 days",
      "options":["A.63:54","B.21:19","C.43:36","D.77:65"],
      "answer":"A.63:54"
    },
    {
      "question":"An estimated 3 out of every 25 men are left-handed,What percent of men are left-handed?",
      "options":["A.18","B.50","C.12","D.6"],
      "answer":"A.C.12"
    },
    ]
  ]

        //   6th grade Science
   
  [
   [
    {
     "question":"I have dry scaly skin,breathe with lungs and lay shelled eggs,What am I?",
      "options":["A.Primates","B.Reptiles","C.Amphibians","D.Cephalopods"],
     "answer":"B.Reptiles"
    },
    {
      "question":"What is the function of the blood cell?",
      "options":["A.Carry messages to all over the body",
                 "B.To control the size of the openings",
                 "C.To carry oxygen around the body",
                 "D.Control the flow of blood"],
      "answer":"C.To carry oxygen around the body"
    },
    {
    "question":"A iron block has a volume of 61 cubic centimeters and a mass of 122 grams.What is its density?",
    "options":["A.14","B.4","C.44","D.2"],
    "answer":"D.2"
     },
     {
      "question":"What abbreviation the Table of elements is K",
      "options":["A.Krypton","B.Holmium","C.Xenon","D.Potassium"],
      "answer":"D.Potassium"

     },
     {
      "question":"What abbreviation in the Table of elements is Sn",
      "options":["A.Tennessine","B.Tin","C.Sulfur","D.Gold"],
      "answer":"B.Tin"

     },
     {
      "question":"What element has a density of 1.7?",
      "options":["A.Fluorine","B.Calcium","C.Carbon","D.Chlorine"],
      "answer":"A.Fluorine"
    },
    {
      "question":"What element has the atomic number of 15?",
      "options":["A.Phosphorus","B.Sodium","C.Holmium","D.Argon"],
      "answer":"A.Phosphorus"
    },
    {
      "question":"What year was Neon discoved as an element?",
      "options":["A.1877","B.1887","C.1898","D.1889"],
      "answer":"C.1898"
    },
    {
      "question":"What element makes up around 18% of the human body",
      "options":["A.Oxygen","B.Carbon","C.Hydrogen","D.Sodium"],
      "answer":"B.Carbon"
    },
    {
      "question":"What are the two types of the earth's crust?",
      "options":["A.Continental crust and Canopy crust",
      "B.Underbody crust and Oceanic crust",
      "C.Continental crust and Oceanic crust","D.Mantle crust and Underbody crust"],
      "answer":"C.Continental crust and Oceanic crust"
    },
    ]
  ]
          // Grade 6 history
  [
    [
     {
      "question":"Who was the fourth President of the United States?",
       "options":["A.John Adams","B.Thomas Jefferson","C.Alexander Hamilton","D.James Madison"],
      "answer":"D.James Madison"
     },
     {
      "question":" Which of these is part of the judicial branch??",
       "options":["A.the Department of Defense","B.Congress","C.the President","D.Supreme Court"],
      "answer":"D.Supreme Court"
     },
     {
      "question":"The First Amendment says the government cannot take away a person _____ or _____?",
       "options":["A.voting rights, rights to own weapons",
                  "B.freedom of speech, freedom of religion",
                  "C.home and private property"],
      "answer":"B.freedom of speech, freedom of religion"
     },
     {
      "question":" Which of these was NOT a member of the original Thirteen Colonies?",
       "options":["A.Maine","B.Pennsylvania,",
                  "C.Delaware","D.Georgia"],
      "answer":"A.Maine"
     },
     {
      "question":" How many men signed the Declaration of Independence in 1776?",
       "options":["A.44","B.33,",
                  "C.56","D.55"],
      "answer":"C.56"
     },
     {
      "question":"Who said the famous quote\"Give me liberty, or give me death!\""?
      "options":["A.Patrick Henry","B.Samuel Adams",
                 "C.Thomas Paine","D.George Washington"],
     "answer":"A.Patrick Henry" 
     },
     {
      "question":" Where was the first shot of the American Revolutionary War fired?"?
      "options":["A.New York","B.Saratoga",
                 "C.Maine","D.Lexington"],
     "answer":"D.Lexington" 
     },
     {
      "question":"In what battle did George Washingtoncending the Revolutionary War?",
        "options":["A.Lexington and Concord,1776","B.the Siege of Yorktown,1781",
                 "C.Battle at Bunker Hill,1775","D.Battle at Chesapeake,1781"],
     "answer":"B.the Siege of Yorktown,1781"
     },
     {
      "question":"What city was the first Capital of the United States?",
      "options":["A.New York,NY","B.Philadelphia, PA",
                 "C.Trenton,NJ","D.Washington DC"],
     "answer":"A.New York,NY"
     },
     {
      "question":"How many stars were on the original American flag?",
      "options":["A.5","B.13",
                 "C.4","D.12"],
     "answer":"B.13"
     }
     
    
   
     ]
   ]
 
 

  
[
  // 7th Grade English
  [
    {
      "question":"What kind of statement is this? — 'The audience's thunderous applause left me completely speechless!'",
      "options":["A.Declarative","B.iterrogative","C.exclamatory","D.question"],
      "answer":"C.exclamatory"
    },
    {
      "question":"Mrs. Shen gave Marshall the solo because he sang it the ______ of everyone who auditioned.",
      "options":["A.Worse","B.best","C.well","D.better"],
      "answer":"B.best"
    },
    {
      "question":"Alphabetically, which word comes first?: upstairs, upon, upward, upper",
      "options":["A.Upper","B.upstairs","C.upon","D.upward"],
      "answer":"C.upon"
    },
    {
      "question":"Which group predates the other?",
      "options":["A.Dinosaurs","B.humans","C.Both","D.Neither"],
      "answer":"A.dinosaurs"
    },
    {
      "question":"When does a basketball team complete its pregame warm-up?",
      "options":["A.Right before the games begins",
      "B.Before the 2nd quarter",
      "C.Right before the games begins",
      "D.Before the fourth quarter"],
      "answer":"C.Right before the games begins"
    },
    {
      "question":"The kayak gave __ and the other couples life jackets and matching helmets?",
      "options":["A.us","B.we","C.them","D.they"],
      "answer":"A.us"
    },
    {
      "question":"The actress gave my best friend and __ her autograph?",
      "options":["A.we","B.I","C.me","D.she"],
      "answer":"C.me"
    },
    {
      "question":"Which is a complete sentence?",
      "options":["A.Butter melts in a skillet",
      "B.Sugar and Salt dissove in water",
      "C.The train was late.",
      "D.Mrs.Spencer is giving away several of her old coats to the charity drive"],
      "answer":"D.Mrs.Spencer is giving away several of her old coats to the charity drive"
    },
    {
      "question":"Which word is an antonym of fictitious?",
      "options":["A.Delightful",
      "B.Beautiful",
      "C.imaginary",
      "D.Real"],
      "answer":"D.Real"
    },
    {
      "question":"Which word is a synonym of maternal?",
      "options":["A.Mature",
      "B.Motherly",
      "C.Fatherly",
      "D.Materialistic"],
      "answer":"B.Motherly"
    }
    
  ]
]

  
[
  // 7th Grade Math
  [
    {
      "question":"John eats 3/5 of a candy bar. What percent of the candy bar does he eat?",
      "options":["A.80%","B.6%","C.35%","D. 60%"],
      "answer":"D.60%"
    },
    {
      "question":"What representes (-4)",
      "options":["A.(+) (-) (+) (+) (+) (+)",
      "B.(-) (-) (+) (+)",
      "C.(+) (-) (+) (-) (-) (-) (-) (-)",
      "D.(-) (+) (-) (-) (-)"],
      "answer":"C.(+) (-) (+) (-) (-) (-) (-) (-)"
    },
    {
      "question":"Calculate: (-8) + (+2) - (-6) = ?",
      "options":["A.(-12)","B.(0)","C.(+4)","D.(+16)"],
      "answer":"B.(0)"
    },
    {
      "question":"What is the greatest common factor of 12 and 16?",
      "options":["A.6","B.3","C.2","D.4"],
      "answer":"D.4"
    },
    {
      "question":"Is -9 − 6 positive or negative?",
      "options":["A.Positive",
      "B.Negative"],
      "answer":"B.Negative"
    },
    {
      "question":"Is 9 + -8 positive or negative?",
      "options":["A.Positive",
      "B.Negative"],
      "answer":"A.Positive"
    },
    {
      "question":"Is -82 + -83 positive or negative?",
      "options":["A.Positive",
      "B.Negative"],
      "answer":"B.Negative"
    },
    {
      "question":"What times itself will give you 625?",
      "options":["A.17","B.62","C.25","D.15"],
      "answer":"C.25"
    },
    {
      "question":"What is the cube root of -343?",
      "options":["A.12","B.7","C.9","D.-7"],
      "answer":"D.-7"
    },
    {
      "question":"What is the cube root of 216??",
      "options":["A.8","B.4","C.-6","D.6"],
      "answer":"D.6"
    }
    
    
    
  ]
]

[
  // 7th Grade Science
  [
    {
      "question":"What is the temperature of a warm grilled cheese sandwich?,Select the better estimate",
      "options":["A.20 degrees F",
                 "B.55 degress C",
                 "C.55 degress F",
                 "D.90 degrees C"],
      "answer":"B.55 degress C"
    },
    {
    "question":"What is the temperature of a cool glass of milk?,Select the better estimate",
     "options":["A.3 degrees C",
               "B.55 degress C",
               "C.2 degress  F",
               "D.45 degrees F"],
"answer":"D.45 degrees F"
    },
    {
      "question":"What is the \"brain\"(command center) of a cell?",
      "options":["A.Mitochondria","B.Nucleus","C.Cytoplasm","D.Ribosomes)"],
      "answer":"B.Nucleus"
    },
    {
      "question":" The ____ membrane allows materials to enter and leave the cell.?",
      "options":["A.Plasma","B.Golgi Body","C.Cytoplasm","D.Ribosomes"],
      "answer":"A.Plasma"
    },
    {
      "question":"What are the three main parts of a cell?",
      "options":["A.cell membrane,mitochondria and cytoplasm",
      "B.Cell membrane,a nucleus,and cytoplasm",
      "C.A nucleus","Vacuole","Golgi Body",
       "D.Golgi Body","Endoplasmic Reticulum","Lysosomes"],
      "answer":"A.cell membrane,mitochondria and cytoplasm"
    },
    {
      "question":"What part of the cell is where energy is made?",
      "options":["A.Cell membrane",
      "B.Cytoplasm",
      "C.Vacuole",
       "D.Mitochondria"],
      "answer":"D.Mitochondria"
    },
    {
      "question":" What responsibity do Chloroplasts have ?",
      "options":["A.Protect the cell",
      "B.Keep the structure of the cell",
      "C.The control center of the cell",
      "D.Where proteins are put together"],
      "answer":"D.Where proteins are put together"
    },
    {
      "question":"What does the chemical symbol Y represent?",
      "options":["A.Xylocaine","B.Ytterbium","C.Titanium","D.Yttrium"],
      "answer":"D.Yttrium"
    },
    {
      "question":"What does the chemical symbol Rh represent??",
      "options":["A.Radium","B.Rhenium","C.Rayon","D.Rhodium"],
      "answer":"D.-7"
    },
    {
      "question":"What does the chemical symbol Ti represent?",
      "options":["A.Thallium","B.Thorium","C.Titanium","D.Tellurium"],
      "answer":"C.Titanium"
    }
    
    
    
  ]
]

  // 7th Grade History
[
  [
     {
      "question":"What country did the Americans and George Washington ally with to eventually defeat the British?",
       "options":["A.Spain","B.Mexico","C.Canada","D.France"],
      "answer":"D.France"
     },
     {
      "question":"The 3/5's Compromise dealt predominantly with what type of people?",
       "options":["A.Slaves","B.Southerners","C.Poor people","D.Northerners"],
      "answer":"A.Slaves"
     },
     {
      "question":"The First Amendment says the government cannot take away a person _____ or _____?",
       "options":["A.voting rights, rights to own weapons",
                  "B.freedom of speech, freedom of religion",
                  "C.home and private property"],
      "answer":"B.freedom of speech, freedom of religion"
     },
     {
      "question":" At its height, what was the slave population in the U.S.?",
       "options":["A.About 4 million","B.About 2 million",
                  "C.About 3 million","D.About 500,000 million"],
      "answer":"A.About 4 million"
     },
     {
      "question":"In what year did American women win the right to vote?",
       "options":["A.1930","B.1923",
                  "C.1920","D.1922"],
      "answer":"C.1920"
     },
     {
      "question":"Who was the first woman to run for President?",
      "options":["A.Sonia Johnson","B.Victoria Woodhull",
                 "C.Linda Jenness","D.Belva Ann Lockwood"],
     "answer":"B.Victoria Woodhull"
     },
     {
        "question":"Which of these honors was Martin Luther King Jr. not awarded?"?
        "options":["A.Nobel Peace Prize",
                 "B.Congressional Gold Medal",
                  "C.Presidential Medal of Freedom",
                  "D.Freedom Award"],
          "answer":"D.Freedom Award" 
     },
     {
        "question":"Why did President Theodore Roosevelt establish the national forest and park systems in the early 20th century?",
        "options":["A.To clear the timberlands for use as industrial areas",
                    "B.To create more areas for the establishment of American Indian reservations",
                    "C.To manage the use of resources and control industrial development in wilderness areas",
                    "D.To stimulate development of a tourist industry to help bring revenue to the states"],
         "answer":"C.To manage the use of resources and control industrial development in wilderness areas"
     },
     {
      "question":"Which of the following was NOT acquired by the United States at the end of the Spanish-American War?",
      "options":["A.Cuba","B.Puerto Rico",
                 "C.The Phillipines","D.Guam"],
     "answer":"A.Cuba"
     },
     {
      "question":"When did the Vietnam War begin?",
      "options":["A.1970","B.1955",
                 "C.1950","D.1972"],
     "answer":"B.1955"
     }
     
    
   
     ]
   ]
 
 

// [
//   // 8th Grade English
//   [
//     {
//       "question":"Choose either A,B,C or D for the correct answer. She  ... at me.",
//       "options":["smile","smiles","Is smiles","is smile"],
//       "answer":"smiles"
//     },
//     {
//       "question":"Choose either A,B,C or D for the correct answer. The person .. you met this morning was my uncle",
//       "options":["who","whom","that","which"],
//       "answer":"who"
//     },
//     {
//       "question":"Which word is a synonym of deficient?",
//       "options":["lacking","dependent","judicious","affluent"],
//       "answer":"lacking"
//     }
//   ]
// ]